# **JAVIER RAMIREZ**

Software Engineer

00	0033770407936							

☐ javier.ramirez.leiva0@gmail.com





https://javier-ramirez-leiva.github.io/



Software engineer, lover of its work and willing to make a difference. I have an international experience in countries such as France and Spain as well as in different domains such as CAD, automotive industry, security and IoT. Currently working for Dassault Systemes in Lyon, France.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

Software Engineer Dassault Systemes | 08/2019-Present

Electrical System Design app inside the CATIA portfolio of the 3DExperience platform from Dassault Systemes.

- C++ development for CAD and PLM applications to design electrical systems on Windows and Linux OS
- CI/CD management. Tools development on python and bash to improve process
- Development of UI elements based on web technologies
- Draft of technical software specifications and unit testing planning
- · Software architecture design focused on re-usability and modules/frameworks
- Model definition for MBSE engineering

Software Engineer Continental | 01/2017-08/2019

AKKA Technologies on behalf of Continental Automotive France SAS. ECU software development to control a Direct Injection Engine inside the new E-Power technology for Nissan.

- Design of the system architecture for a real-time application. Focus on software reliability
- Software development on C/C++ code conforming the AUTOSAR standard
- Scripting (python and perl) to create automatic tests for validation and non-regression
- Team management, AKKA for Continental. Technical orientation and support of other employees
- Creation of software tools to help with task tracking and planning

#### **Software Engineering Intern**

Rockwell Collins | 03/2016-09/2016

Security application to control cameras using the detections made by the radar FMWC PSR-500

- C++ development using the QT framework for Windows and Linux OS
- Planning and specification of validation tests
- Software mock-ups for customer demos

#### **Software Engineering Intern**

Digi International | 02/2014-07/2014

Final Degree Project "Connection of any device to the Cloud Service "Etherios"" at Digi International.

- Study of cloud services, "Internet of Things", Big Data and M2M communications
- Software development in C. Focus on communication socket development

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

ENSEEIHT (Ecole Nationale Supérieure d'Electrotechnique, d'Electronique, d'Informatique, d'Hydraulique et des Télécommunications) 2015 - 2016

#### Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

UPNA (Universidad Publica de Navarra) 2014 - 2015

### **Engineering degree. Electronic engineering**

Universidad de La Rioja 2010 - 2014

# LANGUAGES

Spanish(Native)

• English(Full professional proficienty)

French(Full professional proficienty)

# **SKILLS**

## **Programming Languages**

C, C++ (C++ 11)

Python (3.0), Bash, Perl, VBS

HTML, Javascript, CSS

## **Software Applications**

Visual Studio, QT IDE, Eclipse

Git, JIRA

CATIA, 3D Experience, Matlab

## **Technologies**

Embedded systems

CAD, MBSE

Real-Time, Multicore, AUTOSAR

# **Development Methods**

V Cycle, Agile

Object Oriented Programming, design Patterns, TDD

CI/CD, Unit Testing, Automatic Testing